Finding aid for the Xavier University Core Curriculum Committees records
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Xavier University Core Curriculum Committees records
1966-2010
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)
1.25 linear feet (3 boxes)
Meeting minutes, correspondence, and other documents relating to the work of two Xavier University core curriculum committees. The first committee worked from 1966 to 1968. The second committee worked from 1988 to 1991. A 2008 Diversity Curriculum Requirement Proposal to the Xavier Board of Undergraduate Studies is also included.
XUA-22
History of Undergraduate Core Curriculum committees
Since the 1960's the Xavier University undergraduate core curriculum has undergone major revisions. One occurred from 1966 to 1968, and the other from 1988 to 1991. In 2008 the Gender and Diversity Studies Minor Committee recommended to the Board of Undergraduate Studies changes to the Diversity Requirement in the Core Curriculum. These changes were subsequently approved by the Board of Trustees.
The 1966-1968 committee was overseen by the Xavier Academic Council. The 1988-1991 committee was created by then Xavier president Albert DiUlio,S.J. under the chairmanship of Dr. Norman Barry of the Psychology Department.
Scope and Content
Meeting minutes, correspondence and related documents pertaining to core curriculum study and revision.
Statement of Arrangement
Materials are arranged chronologically by curriculum committee (1966-1968 or 1988-1991), with later materials following, including the 2008 Gender and Diversity Studies proposal.
Restrictions on Access
Restricted access. Please contact the Xavier University Archives staff.
Acquisition Information
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)--Curricula; Curriculum planning--Ohio
Organizations/Corporations:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Academic Council; Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Core Curriculum Committee (1966-1968); Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Core Curriculum Committee (1988-1991); Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Gender and Diversity Studies Minor Committee
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Core Curriculum Planning (1966-1968) Correspondence, 1966 March-November (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Core Curriculum Planning (1966-1968) Correspondence, 1967 March-September (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Core Curriculum Planning (1966-1968) Correspondence, 1967 October-December (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Core Curriculum Planning (1966-1968) Correspondence, 1968 January-March (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Core Curriculum Planning (1966-1968) Correspondence, 1968 March-September (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Core Curriculum Committees (1966-1968) Minutes Philosophy/Theology (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Core Curriculum Committees (1966-1968) Minutes Social Sciences/Behavioral Sciences/Mathematics (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Core Curriculum Committees (1966-1968) Minutes Natural Sciences/Fine Arts/Literature (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Core Curriculum Committees (1966-1968) Minutes Languages/Communication (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Core Curriculum Committees (1966-1968) Summaries, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Core Curriculum Committee (1988-1991) Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Core Curriculum Committee (1988-1991) Minutes, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Core Curriculum Committee (1988-1991) Minutes, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Core Curriculum Committee (1988-1991) Questionnaires, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Core Curriculum Committee (1988-1991) Abstracts of Papers from a Conference on Core Curriculum, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Core Curriculum Committee (1988-1991) Handouts (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Core Curriculum Committee (1988-1991) General Education Statement, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Core Curriculum Committee (1988-1991) Faculty Evaluations of "Old" Core, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Core Curriculum Committee (1988-1991) Departmental Reports, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Core Curriculum Committee (1988-1991) Proposed "New" Core, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Core Curriculum Committee (1988-1991) Proposed "New" Core, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Core Curriculum Committee (1988-1991) Proposed "New" Core, 1990 August-September (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Core Curriculum Committee (1988-1991) Proposed "New" Core Faculty Forum, 1990 September 21 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Core Curriculum Committee (1988-1991) Later Materials Concerning the Core, 1992-2005 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Core Curriculum Revision Diversity Requirement of the Core Curriculum, 2009-2010 (Box 3, Folder 25)